Great. Let's dive into XML. Over the course of my
好 我们来深入研究 XML 吧 在我的职业生涯中
career, I've used XML in a number of different data
我在多个不同的数据科学项目中都使用了 XML
science projects. One of these was working with a large
其中之一是处理大量研究论文
collection of research articles. So, just as an example, here's the
举个例子
original Google paper from Brin and Page when they were
这是布林和佩奇还在斯坦福大学读研究生时
still grad students at Stanford. Now, what I was doing in
写的关于 Google 的论文 我在该项目中所做的
this project is what's known as citation analysis. In citation
就是所谓的引文分析 在引文分析中
analysis, What we're doing is comparing the relative importance of papers
我们要根据论文被多少其它研究论文引用
based on how many other research articles cite them. So
来比较这些论文的相对重要性
for example you could compare the Google paper with some of
例如 你可以将这篇 Google 论文和我的一些著作进行比较
my work. Which receives a much more modest number of
我的著作被引用的数量非常有限
citations compared to the 11,000 that Brin and Page's paper got.
相比之下 布林和佩吉的这篇论文被引用了 11000 次
Now when I was doing my work most of the
当我在写自己的著作时
data that I used was not publicly available. But nowadays the
我所用的数据大多都不是可从公共渠道获得的
same type of data is available and it's encoded as XML.
不过如今 相同类型的这些数据已经编码为 XML 可以供公众访问了
There are quite a few open access publishers, like BioMed Central.
网上有很多公开获取网站 例如 BioMed Central
These publishers produce every article they publish both in a
这些网站会以印刷格式
print form like this, and in .xml. Now, in order to
像这样 以及 .xml 格式发布文章 现在
do something like citation analysis, what we need to do
为了进行引文分析这种工作 我们需要
is access the bibliography for each article. So what I want
访问每篇论文的参考书目
to look at as an example, is how easy it
比如 我要研究的一个例子是
is when you have your data encoded as .xml, to pull
你的数据被编码为 .xml 格式后 会使得
out that type of data, and use it programmatically.
拉取该类数据并以编程方式来使用它变得有多容易
So let's take a look at the references for this paper.
我们来看看这篇论文的参考书目
Here are all of the other papers that this particular
这些是本研究论文所引用的全部的其它论文
research article cites, now let's take a look at the XML
现在我们来看看这些论文的 XML 版本
version of this paper. Here is that exact same paper
这里是同一篇论文
only here, instead of being designed for reading, it is instead
它并不是为能方便阅读而设计的
encoded as data, let's jump down to the bibliography for
而是编码为数据 我们来跳到本论文的参考书目部分
this paper. And here it is, the very beginning of the
在这里 参考书目的开头
bibliography. If we take a look at the print version of
如果我再看看这篇论文的印刷版本
the article again, we can see that it does, in fact,
可以看到 事实上
align with what we're seeing here. So, this type
它确实与我们在这看到的一致 所以
of use of XML is very much what the designers
这种使用 XML 的方式非常贴近 XML 设计者的想法
of XML had in mind, where you have documents that
你有一些文本很多的文档
have lots of text, but text. That you want to
而你想要对文本进行编码
encode so that portions of it, at least, can
以便至少其有一部分
be used programatically, like we might want to do with
可以以编码方式使用 就像我们
a bibliography of a research article. Or the author list
想要对一篇研究论文的参考书目所做的一样 对于
and other data that occurs throughout a document like this.
作者列表或文档中类似这样的其它数据 也都可以这么做